Francis Audric U. Ortiz

Industrial Engineer

A demonstrated industrial engineer seeking to expand the scope of my expertise, driven by a passion for efficiency in all aspects of life, with more than three years of experience in data analysis, troubleshooting, project management, teamwork, and leadership.

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Mar 2019 - present

Senior Planner for Demand and Logistics

The Standard Group

- Manages all internal logistics and demand planning for some of the country's leading restaurants – Yabu: House of Katsu, Ippudo PH, etc.
- In charge of facilitating the monthly demand planning cycle with operations, finance, and marketing managers.
- Leads a logistics team of coordinators and truckers, and multiple ad hoc teams for various projects.

Sep 2019 - present

Head of Supply Chain Excellence

The Standard Group

- Leads interdepartmental projects aimed at improving various end-to-end processes related to supply chain.
- Created a store-level raw material forecasting and ordering module that streamlined hours of work into minutes.
- Developed a leaner internal logistics process flow in collaboration with a third-party warehousing partner.
- Activated the material requirements planning tools for use in SAP upon being upgraded to a newer version.

Aug 2018 - present

Demand Planner

The Standard Group

- In charge of the analysis, formulation, and recasting of all baseline forecasts used by the company.
- Created interconnected Excel databases of historical data from scratch in order to build a foundation for analysis.
- Maintained a sales forecast accuracy of >97% every month across all brands to date.
- Held multiple forecasting workshops for various teams and departments in the company.

Jan 2017 - Aug 2018

Supply Planner & Buyer for Meats and Commodities

The Standard Group

- Responsible for the end-to-end inventory management of all meats, commodities, and local goods for all brands.
- Maintained a lean inventory of all items, with <1% stock outs and overstocks during my entire run.
- Awarded the highest rating in my department by HDY of Selecta during our yearly evaluations.

EDUCATION

2011 – 2016

College of Engineering, University of the Philippines – Diliman BS Industrial Engineering – DOST-SEI Merit Scholarship Awardee

2007 – 2011 Philippine Science High School - Main Campus

PERSONAL DATA

Phone

+63 927 473 6520

E-mail

fauortiz@gmail.com

Address

19 Miguel St., Monterey Hills, San Mateo, 1850 Rizal, PH

KEY SKILLS

- Data Analysis
- Process Improvement
- Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Communication
- Project Management
- Teamwork
- Adaptability

PROFICIENCIES

Microsoft Excel

SAP FRP software

Minitab Statistical software

Lingo Optimization modeling

ProModel Simulation

LANGUAGES

Filipino Native Speaker

English Native Speaker